WWW.MY-SUBS.CO
The harsh Australian outback...
..home to a new breed of player.
Brains...
You don't
need big muscles to fight.
The strongest muscle is the brain.
..versus brawn.
The gladiator style of
competing, it's in my blood.
Go, go, go, go, go! Let's go!
Here to outwit...
Go, go, go!
- Well done!
- Give it everything!
..outplay...
Come on, Survivors! Push it!
- ..and...
- Go!
..outlast.
- Oh!
- Come on!
For 48 days...
I am the puppet master.
Bring it on, baby.
Game on, moll!
..through the most loyal alliances...
My guardian angel is here!
It's Big D's time.
Spicy baby!
- ..and...
- I have two idols.
..spectacular blindsides.
I am unstoppable.
Simon.
- Did you know it was coming?
- Yep.
Laura.
What?!
Emmett.
One by one, they were voted out.
For reals.
And now just three remain.
George.
I came here to raise the bar.
It doesn't matter how much it
hurts, I'm gonna get that crown.
Hayley.
You have to believe in
yourself. You have to be strong.
I have been preparing
for this my whole life.
I have pushed so hard
and I am ready to take
out the title of Sole Survivor.
Flick.
I'm fearless, I'm
courageous and I'm so brave.
I've sacrificed so much
and I'm not giving up now.
Tonight, one will be
crowned Sole Survivor.
It's day 47 and
I've made the final three.
And to think that I've outlasted
21 other Survivor contestants is insane.
But here I am
and I'm proud to represent
the last Brawn standing.
My physical game has
been incredibly strong,
but I've played a great social game.
I have really relied on making
genuine connections with people
and I pride myself on that.
But when I think back to
my experience out here,
I think my journey has been
very different to everyone else's.
I came in here knowing that
I would pride myself
on my physical abilities,
never backing down from a challenge,
putting my body on the line,
and I know I definitely did that,
but I think the real
strength for me out here
was definitely my mental strength.
There's been so many points in this game
where I have been at breaking point,
but I know that my mum
would have wanted me to stay...
..and that's what I've drawn on
as inspiration to keep
going in the game.
I have come up against
the hardest circumstances
and I'm still here
and I'm still fighting.
And knowing that drives
me even harder to win today.
For the past two weeks here
I've been fighting for my life
and it hasn't been easy.
But we've been out here for 47 days
and the winner will be
crowned in less than 48 hours.
And if I have the
opportunity to pitch to the jury,
I feel like I would have their vote.
I'm definitely ready to
put my body on the line,
to fight to get all the way to the end.
I've had a plan since day one -
it's to be a smooth political operative
running a well-oiled campaign.
And that's what I've done.
Gathered cold, hard facts,
campaigned for votes.
And, more importantly,
I've always been one step
ahead of the opposition.
People might think I've gotten
lucky, but I didn't get lucky.
I worked hard to pull
myself from the bottom
and shake the target off
my back every single day.
What I've proven is
that a man with a plan
and a big brain like myself
can outlast a whole heap of
muscle and brawn to succeed.
I have physical limitations,
but I'm not gonna let
that be my downfall.
I might not have won a
single immunity challenge,
but the final challenge is
the only one that matters.
I am really determined to win today.
If it's me in that final two,
I'm in the box seat to
win half a million dollars
and get that crown that
I so rightfully deserve.
But if I lose,
Hayley or Flick take
the power away from me.
I'm not gonna give up
at today's challenge.
It doesn't matter how much it hurts.
I need to get to Election Day,
and that's tomorrow.
So I'm gonna grit my teeth
and I'm gonna get the job done.
My campaign and fight isn't over.
It is an absolute
dream come true to play this game.
I started watching this
game 20 years ago.
I have been researching and
preparing for this moment my whole life.
And now I'm here.
I have a one-in-three shot
of being the Sole Survivor.
It is unbelievable to
think about. I pinch myself.
Now there are only two
people left to get past.
But my competition is fierce.
King George is the epitome of Brains,
and he's played almost
the perfect strategic game.
Flick has been the
ultimate Brawn out here.
She has been a huge physical contender
and built amazing social connections.
But what they don't know
is that I'm the perfect
mix of brain and brawn.
That's a dangerous combination.
This final immunity challenge
is the most important challenge
because it secures you
a spot in the final two
and gives you all the power
to decide who you sit next to.
It could be the make or break
between you and half a million dollars.
Come on in, guys!
In the real world, I research pain.
I've been studying pain for years,
so I know what it
takes to overcome pain.
I know how to push myself to
the edge and how to get past that.
And I'm willing to use all of that
knowledge to help me win today.
Oh, my God.
That looks like torture.
Well, congratulations, guys.
You made it to day 47.
You've endured gruelling conditions
and you've outlasted 21
other people to get this far.
Well done.
Now, are you ready to get to
your final immunity challenge?
- Yes!
- Yes.
Flick, I'm gonna need it back.
Argh!
It'll be coming back soon.
For the last time, immunity
is back up for grabs.
For today's challenge...
..you'll each step into a chamber
standing on very
narrow pegs on the floor
while holding on to
spikes on the ceiling.
At regular intervals,
the ceiling will drop...
..making it more difficult
for you to hold that position.
If at any point you fall
off the pegs or step off,
you're out of the challenge.
Last person standing wins immunity
and a guaranteed spot
at that final tribal council
where you'll have the
chance to pitch to the jury
why you deserve the
title of Sole Survivor
and the half million
dollars that goes with it.
Plus, you'll get to decide
who will be sitting next
to you at that tribal council.
Now, this is a tough challenge,
there's a lot on the line,
so we figured that you might
need a little extra love from home...
..to help you through this.
- Hayley, you ready for this?
- Yeah.
Come on in, guys!
Yes.
Katie.
OK, so, Hayley...
So I know their names,
but who are they to you?
This is Jimmy, my boyfriend,
and Kate, my best mate.
So, how does it feel to
see Jimmy after 47 days?
Oh, my God. It feels so good.
It's just weird for them to be like
actually here and can touch them.
It's so good. It's so nice.
Jimmy, are you surprised
that Hayley is still here?
Yes and no.
She's absolutely amazing
and incredible and so strong
and, oh... I'm just, like, so amazed.
Hayley, those are all
the correct answers, right?
Yeah. Keep saying nice things.
What would it mean to
Hayley to win this game?
Oh, it would be... it
would be life-changing.
She's already done so amazing.
So anything beyond this
is just an absolute bonus.
- So, George.
- Yes.
Who is it that you'd love to see today?
I've really been missing my mum.
It's just kind of been building,
so, hopefully she's there.
Well, let's find out.
Come on in, guys.
Oh, my God.
I'm so close.
Hello. Hi.
Look at you. Look at you.
Alright, George, can you
give me an introduction?
This is my mum, Maria,
and this is my sister, Pamela.
- OK.
- Yeah.
- So, Maria.
- Yes.
When George came to you and said,
"Mum, I'm going to go play Survivor,"
what did you think?
I wasn't that surprised,
because I know once he puts his
mind to anything, he can do whatever.
Day one he stood in front
of me in his bowling whites.
They're bowling dirty browns now.
You're going to have to
wash them in a few days.
That's fine. That's fine. I
look forward to doing that.
So, George, how much
have you missed your mother?
I have missed my mother.
Whilst I'm physically depleted,
I'm here for you guys, so...
And we're here for you.
Flick.
Yes.
I know this game has been
especially tough for you.
- So let's get you some love.
- Yeah.
Oh...
It's so good to see you.
It's hard to keep it together.
That's alright.
It's really hard to keep it together.
Alright, Flick, who do you have here?
Oh, I have my beautiful partner, Mitch.
Who I haven't seen in
four and a half months.
So it's amazing to see him.
My beautiful best friend who I've
been friends with for over 20 years.
What does it mean to have
these guys here with you today?
Words can't describe for me right now.
Like, it's hard enough being
out here away from your family
and losing my mum while I've been here.
And all I wanted is the
people I'm closest to,
for support, and not having
that has been incredibly tough.
So...
..just to see their faces.
Oh, I couldn't ask for
anything more. I really couldn't.
Mitch, after 47 days, Flick
is still here, still fighting.
Does that surprise you?
Not at all. No. She's amazing.
I would have been surprised
if she didn't get this far, so...
She's just... just incredible.
So, so proud of her. Yeah.
She's the strongest
person I know, by far.
Very strong.
OK, loved ones, you guys are going
to be cheering on from the bench today.
Hayley, Flick, George,
we're going to get to it.
- I'll just hug you.
- Yes.
I'd forgotten how tall you were.
Oh...
This is the time to do it, George.
Alright, guys, let's
step up into position.
Alright.
Final immunity.
This challenge...
..is now on.
So here we are, we're
down to two Brains...
..one Brawn.
All you gotta do
is outlast two other people,
and you will have a chance
to pitch to the jury,
a shot at that half million dollars.
You could move around that bed of nails.
Left to right.
Front to back.
At some stage,
I'm going to lower that ceiling.
Making it more difficult
to hold your position.
Fall or step off the pegs...
..you're out of the challenge.
No pressure.
15 minutes into this challenge.
George, how are you feeling?
Well, I'm glad I lasted more
than four minutes today.
Yeah, me too.
I've been waiting 47
days for my turn to do it!
Let me win!
So, you gonna let me win, Flick?
No, I need this.
I don't think I'm going
to final two if I don't.
You guys been up there for 30 minutes.
So, that position
was pretty easy, right?
I think it's time to make
it a little more interesting.
- Uh-huh.
- Oh.
On the count of three,
I'm going to lower that ceiling.
Oh, wow.
Here we go.
Three...
..two...
..one.
Oh, my God.
Oh, shit.
On the count of three...
..I'm gonna lower that ceiling.
Three, two...
..one.
Impossible to stand up straight now.
Without your head
bumping into those spikes.
Everyone's got a slightly different take
on how to deal with this new position.
Flick squatting down,
stretching her arms out.
George leaning forward.
Tippy-toes, eh?
Hayley on those ballerina points.
Those pedestals are gonna start
grinding into the soles of your feet.
Like hundreds of tiny knives.
The pain is only
increasing at this point.
Every time you move your hands,
every time you make an adjustment...
..you risk slipping off.
Just tiny adjustments,
that's all you can make.
I'm joking.
Fresh dust in the afternoon.
I love a bit of dust in the eyeballs.
Flick, why are you smiling?
Oh... I just find it funny.
Like, why am I doing this to myself?
So, why are you doing this, Flick?
I am doing this for my family.
They are my biggest inspiration.
I mean, that's the reason I'm here.
That's why I wanna
win, I wanna win for them.
What about you, George?
Why are you still up there?
I'm here for my family as well.
I've proved what I needed
to prove here already -
that I'm a great operator -
but I'm now here for them.
We're here for you.
- I would have given up by now.
- No, no, don't give up.
Keep going.
Hayley, why are you up there?
I just wanna prove
to myself I can do it.
I feel like I can, I feel
like my body can do it
and my mind can do it,
and I just wanna hold on.
I think we should
turn it up a little bit.
Or in this case, turn it down.
We're gonna bring it down again.
Three...
..two...
..one.
Those quads.
Not too many comfortable positions now.
Fewer and fewer options
the lower that ceiling gets.
It's just like you're on a surfboard.
Yeah.
God, look at the sky behind us.
Whoa.
Oh, that looks so good.
That will be someone's
last sunset, tonight.
Guys, you've been
up there for 3.5 hours.
Everyone checking each other out.
Wondering who has the
most in the tank on day 47.
We're now at the point where it
switches from a physical challenge
to a mental challenge.
Those pegs have gotta feel
like daggers in your feet now,
boring through the flesh.
Nothing easy about Survivor.
George clearly in a lot of pain now.
Come on, George.
Moving around...
..a lot now.
Trying different positions.
Looking for anything
that will offer some relief.
We believe in you,
George. Keep fighting.
You've got this, George, come on.
I'm right here.
Everyone still in it.
Everyone still with a
shot at that necklace.
George continues to fight.
Stepped away from a
couple of other challenges.
Not this time.
How long can he keep this going for?
I think I've gotta do it.
I can't do any more.
- Well done, George.
- Good job, George.
And after over 4.5 hours,
George has had enough.
He's out of the challenge.
- Yeah, great effort, George.
- That's amazing.
I'm so proud of you.
- My hands couldn't hold on anymore.
- That's fine, son.
- You did so good.
- That's fine.
It's now down to Hayley and Flick.
We now have a showdown.
Fighting it out for that necklace.
A guaranteed spot final two.
Incredible effort from
both Hayley and Flick.
Now it's time to drop
those spikes one last time.
Hold on, Hayley. You got this.
I'm gonna count you guys in.
Three...
..two... one.
Oh, shit.
It's now exactly one metre...
..between the peg and
the spike above your head.
Very little room to move around now.
If it was painful before...
..this is gonna become
a whole new level.
Keep going, Hayley. Keep going.
Flick, really struggling.
Gasping for air.
Pain is just unbearable.
Meanwhile, Hayley is like a statue.
Eyes closed, super focused.
An expert on pain management.
If Hayley is in pain,
she's not showing it.
Maybe that's part of her strategy.
I don't know if I can
go much longer, hey?
Yes, you can.
Come on. A little bit longer.
Come on, Flick.
Flick in excruciating pain,
really trying to push.
Flick's arms failing her now.
Doing everything she can to hang on.
Getting dangerously close
to the end of those spikes.
Come on. dig deep.
Find that strength, Flick.
That last little bit.
Come on, we're all here. You're OK.
You're OK.
Oh...
You've got this. Keep
breathing through it.
Stay there, Flick. Stay in the zone.
That's good.
Amazingly, Flick is still in it.
Finding something in a reserve tank.
That's it. Keep it up.
You're strong. You can do this.
Hayley's body shaking now.
Who's going to reach their limit first?
Keep going, Hayley.
Keep going. So strong.
Yeah. Come on, Flick. Come on!
Literally nowhere to go.
Nowhere to hide.
It's just you and the pain.
I need help. I need help. I need help.
- Getting off.
- Getting off?
- Yeah. I need help.
- Alright.
Well done.
Are you right?
After five hours and 17 minutes,
Flick can no longer endure the pain.
Well done, Hayley.
Hayley wins immunity.
And guarantees herself a spot,
in the final tribal council.
That was amazing.
It really was amazing.
- Oh, my God. Oh.
- Good job.
Hayley, come on over.
Well done.
Congratulations.
Individual immunity is yours.
Guaranteed a 50%
shot at winning the game
and the half million
dollars that goes with it.
One big decision left,
which of these two is going
to join you at that fund tribal?
And which is going to become the
ninth and final member of the jury?
Unfortunately, you won't
have much time to think about it
because we're going
to go straight to tribal.
We'll see you soon. Well done.
Good job, Hayley. Amazing. Amazing.
Oh, thank you so much for coming.
Whatever happens happens. OK?
I want you to be happy
that you got this far.
- OK?
- Yeah. I am happy.
You're OK.
Losing that challenge
was really devastating for me.
But my time is not up yet in the game.
And I still have one more
chance to convince Hayley
to take me to final tonight.
- Bye.
- See you, guys.
- See you. Love you.
- Bye, George.
And I'm not going to
go down without a fight.
I'll now bring in the
members of our jury.
Baden,
Gerald,
Laura, Emmett,
Andrew, Dani,
Wai
and Cara, voted out
at the last tribal council.
Well done, Hayley.
Well done today, guys. I mean,
that was a brutal challenge.
And you guys gave it everything.
But after five hours and 17 minutes,
it was Hayley who
took that necklace again.
Hayley, you seemed confident
from the get-go in that challenge.
Did your confidence ever waver?
Oh, I knew that it was
going to be gruelling
because these two guys
really wanted it as well.
And I took everything that I
have ever learned about pain
and I used that today
to make sure that I was the
last one wearing this necklace.
So, I'm certainly
very proud of this win.
Honestly, it was an amazing
performance, like, incredible.
Well, Flick and George,
you should both be very
proud of your efforts today,
but, Hayley, you now have
the difficult decision to make -
who are you going to send to the jury
and who are you going to take
with you to the final tribal council?
What's going through
your head right now?
There's a lot of things
going through my head.
I think ultimately this decision
has to come down to who
do you think you can sit next to
and convince the jury that you
have played a better game than them.
But both of these guys
have played great games.
Yeah. And so it's a
tough decision for me.
Flick, let me ask you this,
why should Hayley
take you to the final two?
I don't know if I've ever seen
anyone play like George before.
I look at George and
his game is amazing.
And I would be worried about
coming up against someone
who is so wise with their words.
And I feel like that
is what has the power
to sway the jury in the end.
So, George, Flick has
laid out all the reasons
why Hayley shouldn't take you.
Why shouldn't Hayley take Flick?
Because if Hayley wants to win $500,000,
she should try and beat me.
Are you saying that Flick has a
better chance of winning than Hayley?
I think that Flick has more
locked in votes with that jury.
And based on that, you have
to navigate a very thin line
to get to the crown.
My understanding is that there
are votes up for grab on that jury,
but not all of them.
And you have to factor that
into your decision tonight.
I disagree. I don't think
I have locked in votes.
I don't think anyone
has locked in votes.
I mean, yeah, everyone
here is closer to certain people
that are sitting over
there on that jury.
But we can't expect that just
because we're close to these people
that they're going to
vote for us in the end.
Alright. Well, Hayley,
tonight, your vote is
the only one that counts.
And before we go and do that,
George, what do you
want to say to Hayley?
Queen Haley?
What is a queen without a king?
Save me from the guillotine tonight
and take me to your final two tomorrow
and let the king and queen
battle it out for the crown.
Flick, is there anything
that you wanted to say?
Oh, well...
..for me to get to the end would
be a massive achievement...
..with everything that I've
experienced on this crazy journey.
Just to know that I never gave up,
no matter what
challenge I was faced with.
It would just reinforce why I'm here
and give me the satisfaction
that I made it to the end.
But tonight, the power
lies in Hayley's hands
and Hayley will do what
is best for Hayley tonight.
And I hope that's me.
Well, Flick and George,
you should both be very
proud of your efforts today,
but Hayley, you now have
the difficult decision to make -
who are you going to send to the jury
and who are you going to take
with you to the final tribal council?
It's time for you to cast that vote.
Oh, man...
I'll go collect the vote.
I'll read the vote.
22nd person voted out
and ninth and final
member of our jury...
..Flick.
You need to bring me your torch.
- I'm sorry.
- No. It's all good.
It's all good.
Congrats.
- Thanks, George.
- You really did.
Thanks, George.
Proud of you guys.
I'm just so grateful and thankful
to have made it to the
top three with you guys.
Thank you.
- Flick, the tribe has spoken.
- Yes, they have.
Time for you to go.
Wow.
Well, congratulations,
you are the final two.
You've gone as far as
you can go in this game
and now the power shifts
to these guys, the jury.
So, I suggest you get some rest
and think about how are
you going to convince them
that you deserve the
title of Sole Survivor
and the half million that goes with it.
- Grab your torches and head on out.
- Oh, yeah. I need that.
Congrats.
- See ya.
- Bye.
Goodbye. See you.
Yum!
Oh, finally!
- Oh, my God.
- Oh!
Bacon.
- Oh, my God. More bacon. Eggs.
- Eggs.
Oh, my God. Oh, yum.
Last night, I won the
final immunity challenge.
I had the necklace and I got
to choose who went home.
And I sent Flick home.
To send her home was
the most difficult thing
I've had to do in this game.
I grew really close
to Flick in this game,
but it was the only
thing I could think to do
to give myself a chance to win.
This is the moment
I've been waiting for.
- Ooh!
- Yay!
- Top two.
- Let it pour.
I think that my game
stacks up against George's.
His strategy has been incredible,
but what he missed out on
is playing a physical game,
and he's kind of rubbed
some people the wrong way.
To 48 days of fun,
and good luck tonight.
- Yeah, may the best man win.
- Cheers.
I have a winning game because it
encompasses all aspects of Survivor.
- Let's cook.
- Let's get started with the food.
I've been incredibly physical.
I took out four individual
immunity necklaces.
I've played very smart, strategic
moves and taken out big players.
And I've made great social bonds.
Now I'm at the end because I
have come up against 22 people
and I outmanoeuvred them.
Last day in Survivor.
I know. This is gonna be a fun day.
I've spent a lot of the
last decade studying
because I wanted to have
a career that helped people.
But it means that I've
had to sacrifice so much.
Half a million dollars would
completely change my life.
I can buy a house, buy a car.
It would be incredible.
To start a family.
That would mean the world to me.
I didn't win many rewards off
Fire tribe, but do you know what?
I'm happy to get to day
48, top two breakfast.
Never in a million years would
I have thought on day one,
when I stood on that mat in my
white Bankstown Sports Club outfit,
that I would be getting ready
to make a pitch to the jury
at tonight's tribal council.
Well, if my mum was proud of me
for doing that final immunity challenge,
wait until she sees
me stirring tomatoes.
Whoo!
Yesterday's immunity challenge
reminded me why I'm here.
It's my family. I came here for them.
My hardworking father and mother,
they've been working for over 40
years, and they've worked enough.
I came here to win half a million
dollars that clears their debt
and allows them to
finally enjoy their life.
My family have been there for
me and I wanna be there for them.
I'm gonna make sure
that I can deliver for them.
Breakfast of the king and the queen.
We need this breakfast 'cause
we've got a battle ahead of us today.
- Mm-hm.
- It is gonna be a huge tribal.
I've had a target on my back
for almost every single day
here in the game.
People have been firing shots at me
but they haven't been able to hit me,
and that hasn't been through luck,
it's been through sheer hard work.
I knew I had to outwit and
outplay people to outlast them,
and that's what I did.
Almost every single
person is sitting on that jury
because I orchestrated
their elimination.
I'm hoping that that jury
doesn't have grievances.
What I need to do with
the jury tonight is show them
that you don't need to
like me to vote for me,
you just need to acknowledge
that what I've done
is worthy of the title.
- That's it for the Fire tribe.
- That's it.
King George against Queen
Hayley truly is a battle royale.
And I'm going to snatch the
crown that I so rightfully deserve.
Then there were two.
I'll now bring in the
members of our jury.
Baden, Gerald,
Laura,
Emmett, Andrew...
..Dani, Wai...
..Cara and Flick...
..voted out at the last tribal council.
- So, here we are...
- Yeah.
..day 48 and your final tribal council.
You guys have gone as far as
you can possibly go in this game.
Tonight the power
now shifts to the jury.
Nine people that you had a
hand in voting out either directly
or indirectly will now
decide which of you two
deserves the title of Sole Survivor
and the half a million
dollars that goes with it.
This is how it's gonna work. You'll
each make an opening statement.
This is your chance to pitch to the jury
why you think you
deserve to win this game.
Then the jury will address
you, they'll ask you questions
and you'll answer them.
And then they'll have a chance
to respond to your answers
in an open forum.
Once everyone's had their say,
the jury will then go up to vote
to decide who wins Australian
Survivor: Brains v Brawn.
George, this is the moment
you've been waiting for.
You now get to address the jury.
Well, good evening, jury.
To my friends and my frenemies,
what a journey we've all been on.
I came here as a political operative.
I've never been camping before.
When I stepped on that mat in
day one and saw the lot of you,
I told myself, "What the hell
have I gotten myself into?"
But I've been overcoming
personal barriers since the very start.
And it worked like this, phase
one was controlled dysfunction,
it was controlled chaos.
I realised I was in a
minority from the outset.
That tribe had a dynamic that was
gonna pick off the physically weak.
That's why I had to
change the tone of the game
at the very first Brains tribal council.
Because if it relied
on an interpretation
of physical strength
as being the key criteria,
I would be right at the
bottom of the pecking order.
I made a decision to save
who I thought needed saving.
Giving Wai a second chance
made sure that I got here.
My game moved to a second phase
at tribe swap. It was maintenance.
And at the maintenance phase,
I had to rely on my social game.
I became an honorary Brawn
and that set me up for
the final phase of my game.
Dynasty.
When we got to the merge I
realised my best prospect of success
was going back to the Brains.
Because the Brawn
alliance had what I don't -
its physical prowess.
So I had to cook up
a very, very risky plan.
I was playing two
alliances as a covert agent.
I risked my entire future in the
game, when I was in a comfortable,
safe Brawn majority, to help all the
Brains, because I was Brain strong.
And in working with the Brains
I carried a minority to a majority.
I'm not ashamed to say that
I took opportunities to strike.
You were all a threat.
Because if I didn't strike at you,
you would have striked at me.
I came here to show that
brains can trump over brawn
if you have a good strategy.
A man with a plan is dangerous,
and I've been very
dangerous in this game.
I've been frank, I've been fearless,
but I've also been 100% me.
I know I'm not perfect, I know I'm
not gonna win Miss Congeniality,
but I've given it my damn all
to outwit, outplay
and outlast 22 players.
And the only thing that my
game is missing is my crown.
This is my election day.
This is your time to
go to the ballot box
and give me the crown that I
think my strategic game deserves.
Wow.
Hayley...
..now it's your shot.
Hey, jury.
I'm sitting here in front of you today
and I am genuinely proud of
the game that I have played.
I started in the Brains tribe
and I was in a majority alliance,
but I always knew what the
minority alliance was doing.
And I had the power to
swing any of those votes.
And that is where the
power lies in this game.
It's not the person at the top
who is dictating who goes home,
it's the person who sits in the
middle, who has all the information
and can decide if they
wanna swing or not.
When it came to the vote for George,
I made a decision that I wanted
to swing and take out Joey.
And Baden and Wai
came with me on that vote
and we took out one of the
biggest players in the Brains tribe -
amazing Joey.
And the timing for that was perfect
because it was just before
we went to tribe swap.
But...
..as Survivor goes, tribe
swap is a little bit of luck,
and we didn't end up with that luck.
We were in a tribe with
four Brain and five Brawn.
Luckily, at that point, I had found
myself with my public immunity idol.
And that idol that I found,
I managed to play to maximum
effect over three different tribals.
First, we were in this
minority, but I had a choice -
I could let Baden go home
and use the idol to save myself,
or I could tell the Brawn
I am going to flip a coin,
one of us will use the idol
and you're gonna have to break.
And it worked.
And suddenly we had control of
the game, and Shannon went home.
Next, it was the Simon vote.
Someone who had two idols in his pocket.
I needed to play my part in that vote,
and that was I needed to hold that idol.
I had to trust in these new
relationships I had made...
..and I needed to
trust that if I held it,
then he wouldn't play
his and he would go home.
Finally, it was the Kez vote, and
George did leak information to me,
but I'm the one who
had to execute that move.
I had to make the decision
if I wanted to expose myself,
risk playing an idol for someone
who wasn't me, play it on Laura,
save her, and then cover it all
up by saying that I was the oracle.
That idol lasted three votes and
got me much further in the game.
But no-one plays a perfect game
and I ended up at Redemption Rock.
That was a really crucial
turning point for me.
I was playing hard and
fast and really strategic.
I had to adapt my gameplay.
But first I had to get
back in this game,
and I was up against Baden,
a Tour de France winner.
And winning that
redemption rock challenge
gave me the confidence to
really test myself physically.
I came back thinking maybe that is
something that I CAN lean into here,
and I ended up winning the
immunity necklace four times -
the most out of anyone here.
And I'm really proud of the way
that I've managed to
play a physical game.
I know that this game is
about outwitting socially,
outlasting physically and
outplaying strategically...
..and I think I am the
one person left here
who has done all three of
those things really, really well.
And I'm really grateful
and proud that I'm still here.
Very good.
Alright, jury, you have heard
two very excellent pitches.
Now it is your turn to ask questions.
Alright, jury. You have heard
two very excellent pitches.
Now it is your turn to ask questions.
Laura, wanna go first?
Sure.
Well, on behalf of all of us,
I want to say congratulations.
Thanks.
This has been an epic journey
and to make it all the way to
the end is bloody incredible.
And just so you know, I have
not solidified anything in my mind.
So, to hear your pitches tonight,
but also your answers
is really important to me.
And I know it is for a
lot of other people here.
George, what have you learnt
about yourself in this game?
Thank you for your question, Laura,
and I think it's a very good question.
So, every night when I lie down
wide awake in the freezing cold,
I do reflect on what I
learn every single day.
I'm just a boy from suburban Bankstown.
I don't think anyone
would ever have expected
that I would last 48 days
in these harsh conditions.
But I've done it.
And what I've learned
is that I can do anything
when I put my mind to it.
I've come up with a lot of
innovative ways to survive out here
because I couldn't just rely on my body.
I gathered intelligence
like a secret covert agent.
I listened to Gerald and Flick
talking to Dani by the pool.
I was literally hanging
on the edge of a cliff.
I listened to Hayley and Wai
talking at the well.
Andrew didn't realise that I was
lying down like a snake in the grass
on a rock right behind him.
I just learned to survive,
and I'm really proud of that.
OK, Cara. You're next.
Hayley, did you come in intending
to lie, manipulate and deceive,
or did it just come about organically?
I came into this game
as a really big fan,
and I absolutely knew that a part
of this game is lying and deceiving.
And to be honest, that's a part
of what I do in my real world.
Like I'm a researcher and I
run experiments on people.
We have to run placebos.
That means we have people coming in
and we're giving them
entirely fake treatments.
And I wanted to bring
those skills into this game.
And I had absolutely
no worries in doing that.
If you have a plan in place, you
can't let someone else have a plan
that is going to counteract that.
You have to misdirect.
So I am really happy and proud
about the ways that I have
managed to misdirect people
and lie and deceive.
It's not a dirty word
to me in this game,
and I feel like I'm sitting here
because I managed to do that
really well at just the right times.
Alright, Andrew.
Oh, right, it was about
six weeks ago that I said,
"You know what? George and Hayley,
"they're definitely the most
dangerous characters in this game."
And, yeah, I don't know what part
of the memo youse didn't get, but...
- I believed you.
- There it is.
I'm going to keep it short and sharp.
What regrets did you have and
what would you do differently?
I'm going to be frank. I don't have any.
Because every move I've done,
despite being risky,
has got me to this seat.
I do have some regrets in this game,
and the one that I think
is the most obvious for me
is the one that landed
me at Redemption Rock.
I made the decision to expose
George as the double agent
and Emmett told everybody
else and my game was blown.
So I think that if I could
go back and do that again,
I would have only told that to Dani.
It would have been a
very different outcome.
I'm glad you mentioned
that you've got regrets
because at the Outback
Retreat, you sat next to Flick and I
and you told us that you were all in.
You had all the power in the game.
So what was the point
at poking us even further?
And do you regret it now
that we now have the power?
I knew that if I didn't say that
I was going to work with you
and give you confidence
that you would start swinging
at me and it would risk my game,
so I had to misdirect you
so that you didn't come
up with an alternative plan.
It was hard to have to
deceive you in that way,
but I don't regret it.
I think it was necessary
because I don't think you
would have gone down easily.
I appreciate the honesty and
my vote is up for grabs tonight
and I want to see
people owning their lives
and owning their gameplay,
no matter who gets stung by it.
Alright, Gerald, what have you got?
Alright. Um...
Awesome work on getting here, guys.
So, my question to you is, if
this game restarted right now
with the 11 people that are here,
who do you think would work
with you on this jury right now?
Gerald, for me, knowing
what you've all seen
and how I've played this game...
..the answer should be none of you,
because whilst on first impressions,
no-one expected me to be a threat,
look at me now.
I am going to take almost the
opposite approach to George
in saying that I feel like I
would work with all of you
if I came back in this game.
And I think that you
would all work with me
because you all wrote my name down
and somehow I came back and
you still trusted me to work with you.
I think that that shows
that I have the ability
to adapt my game
and to get you to trust me
even when maybe you shouldn't.
I think you're probably right.
I couldn't really see you coming
back from Redemption Rock.
I congratulate you on proving me wrong,
but I think you believed it too.
Alright, Dani. What do you want to ask?
George.
So, I... being a challenge
beast and also a Brawn,
you can appreciate that I respect
physicality and never giving up.
And when it comes to challenges,
you decided not to play a big
part of the game, the outplay.
I've been saying the whole
time, you can't just be strategic.
You'd like to believe that
you are one of the best players
in Australian Survivor history.
So when you sat down on challenges,
explain to the jury why you gave
up on such a big part of the game.
So, George, me being a
challenge beast and also a Brawn,
you can appreciate that I respect
physicality and never giving up.
And when it comes to challenges,
you decided not to play a big
part of the game, the outplay.
You'd like to believe that
you are one of the best players
in Australian Survivor history.
So when you sat down on challenges,
explain to the jury why you gave
up on such a big part of the game.
Thanks, I appreciate your
question, Dani, about my physicality,
And I'm happy to
provide an answer to you.
So, I know what my strengths and
weaknesses are as an individual.
I know I'm not good enough if
the only criteria is physicality.
I know that. That's my weakness.
And I papered over my weaknesses
this entire game because I had to.
But my greatest strength is my strategy.
It's my ability to be
a political operative.
Alright, Flick. You're up.
OK, so, Hayley,
we've had many discussions,
none of which I think were truthful.
Yeah.
Why did you never want to work with me?
Oh, I did want to work with you.
Ultimately, the aim was that we
would work with you, come merge.
But we got there and
you didn't come with us.
And then we got so far into the game
that it was no longer about
who would I like to work with.
It was about who do
I think that I can beat.
And I know I got called a flipper,
but I know that when I did
flip, I flipped at the right time.
When George had exposed
himself by using his idol for Cara
and we were all
thinking of voting him out,
I decided that instead of going
with you, Dani and Emmett
flipped over to George, Cara and Wai
because I knew if I was
with the four of them,
I was the strongest
physical player there.
So that set me up to be
sitting here in the final two.
And I think that was one of the
most important moves I made.
OK.
So, George, how much have you relied
on lying and manipulation in this
game to get you to where you are?
I would say when you assess my game,
you should look at
the intent of my actions
and the intent of the outcome.
I had to do what needed to be done.
So in terms of the degree
of lying and manipulation,
I thread a very fine
line, but I had to do it.
It's Survivor.
Alright, Emmett. What
do you got, brother?
I'm going to start off by saying,
George, the cockroach of
Bankstown couldn't squash him,
couldn't figure out how
to get you out of the game.
And I'm sure these Brains crew
couldn't figure out how to get
you out of the game as well.
So I respect you for that.
And I think you've done an amazing job
at evading near-death experiences.
And I love all the powerful
moves that you played.
But from my perspective, the
thing that I'm going to touch on
in terms of your comparison
between the two of you
is George, you've burned
bridges with everyone.
You've not only deceived
people and lied to people
and voted people off,
but you've done it in a way that's
rubbed so many people the wrong way.
If you had the chance to do this again,
would you play the game the same
and still be spinning lies
and destroying relationships
with everyone in the game?
- That's my question.
- Thank you. Thank you, Emmett.
And that's a very tough question,
but I appreciate the
level of thought and detail
that you put into it.
The difficult thing about Survivor
is that fine line between strategy
and what's interpreted as lying.
I don't shy away from the fact
that I caused each and every one of you
to be there in some degree
or another, except for Baden.
I own that.
I still feel like you're
beating around the bush
of what I'm actually trying to ask.
I accept what you're saying,
but the decision that
you have to make tonight
is based on who you think
deserves the title of Sole Survivor.
I think I deserve it. I'm
proud of my resume.
I don't know how the
hell else to say it, man.
But, like, my question was, if
you had a chance to do it again,
would you push
yourself harder physically
or build more relationships
without burning so many bridges?
I don't think so.
If it's not good enough
for you, that's fine,
we're all entitled to our opinion.
But I reiterate, I
wouldn't change anything.
I needed to do what I did to get here.
And that has resulted in
eight of the nine jury members
sitting on that bench.
I've put you there. I blindsided you.
And I'm sitting here right now
with the best resume in the game.
And if that's the criteria that
you're gonna assess your vote with,
give me your vote.
So, Hayley, how do you see your
game and George's game differently?
And why did you decide to
ultimately take George to the end,
because you both have
such strong strategic games?
My game is not just about
having a resume strategically.
I think that my game
is way more rounded.
I knew that I would be up
against a formidable speaker
and someone who is funny
and engaging and charismatic.
But I still back my game
in sitting next to him tonight.
I have played a really strategic game
and I know I've played
a really physical game
and I also played a
really strong social game.
But if you have all of those things,
then you're probably
going to end up on the jury.
So I had to cover up
some of my strategic play
and I needed to manipulate my
threat level so that I could get here.
There's no point playing a big game
unless I can get to the final two
and prove that my game was good.
I feel like there is a number of moves
that I was really proud of in this game.
But the physical aspect
is what surprised me the
absolute most out here.
I came up against some
huge endurance athletes,
some challenge beasts,
and I managed to
outwrestle an MMA fighter,
I managed to outbalance
a big wave surfer,
I pushed myself past the point
that I possibly thought I could
in some really tough
endurance challenges.
And lastly, on that
very crucial challenge,
I used everything I
knew about pain to win.
I think that my game encompasses
what it means to be a Brain,
but what it means to be a Brawn.
It is about giving 110% in the physical,
in the social and in the strategic.
And I have done that.
Alright, guys.
You should have all the
information you need now to decide
who you think deserves
the title of Sole Survivor
and the half million that goes with it.
Remember, tonight,
you're voting for a winner.
For the last time,
it is... time to vote.
Alright, guys, you should have
all the information you need now
to decide who you think
deserves the title of Sole Survivor
and the half million that goes with it.
Remember tonight, you
are voting for a winner.
For the last time,
it is... time to vote.
Baden, you're up.
George, the cockroach that never dies.
I'm actually voting
for you to win tonight.
I think you've played
an amazing, mastermind,
covert game of Survivor.
The only thing I can say
is that, Hayley,
you outwitted, outlasted and outplayed.
So congratulations, babe.
Both of you had really
compelling arguments,
but I had to go with you.
I think you have been an amazing
player in the game strategically.
I'll go count the votes.
Well, there is no doubt
that this has been an incredible season.
The only thing left to
do, Hayley and George,
is read the votes.
But... a moment like this
really should be shared
with the people you love the most.
Come on in, guys.
Yes!
Come here. So good.
- Maria...
- Yes.
..how proud are you
of your son right now?
There aren't enough words to
tell you how proud I am of him.
I love him very much.
Pamela, this seems to be a
really emotional moment for you.
I'm just so proud of
him for making it this far,
and no matter what,
I love him very much.
George, what's going
through your head right now?
No matter what the outcome is,
there's gonna be a deserving winner.
I'm hoping it's me. I've got
my fingers and toes crossed.
I'm praying to the Survivor
gods, Macedonian Jesus,
anyone who'd listen.
And I'm just hoping that
I can get the job done.
So, Jimmy, do you think Hayley
deserves to take this one out?
Yeah, of course.
But I'm incredibly biased.
Kate, you've known Hayley a long time.
What do you think it means to her
to be standing here living
out her childhood dream?
Hayley had a Survivor
themed 21st birthday
back in the day,
tiki torches and everything.
I know it just means
everything to her to be here.
Wow. True Survivor geek.
I was hiding that.
Hayley, what's going
through your head right now?
I never even dreamed I
would be able to play this game,
let alone stand here at the final
two and have a chance to win.
And I am so proud to be standing here,
I'm proud to be standing next to George.
He's played a phenomenal game.
And, yeah, I can't wait
to see what's in that urn.
Alright, guys, let's get to it.
Remember, these votes are for a winner.
And with nine jury members,
it only takes five votes.
I'll read the votes.
First vote...
..Hayley.
George.
One vote Hayley, one vote George.
Hayley.
That's two votes
Hayley, one vote George.
George.
We're tied.
Two votes Hayley, two votes George.
Hayley.
Three votes Hayley, two votes George.
Four votes Hayley, two votes George.
Winner of Australian Survivor
Brains versus Brawn, Hayley.
Oh, congratulations!
Hayley, congratulations.
Not only are you half
a million dollars richer,
but you are Sole Survivor,
Brains versus Brawn.
Well done,
Queen! You deserve it!
Whoo!
I am in complete
shock at what's just happened.
I am the Sole Survivor.
I have learned that I can do
way more than I think I can.
I survived for 48 days.
I made massive blindsides.
I was a physical beast out here
and I never thought I would be.
Well done, Hayley.
I'm proud of being able to come out here
and play a really big strategic game.
I didn't want to hide in the shadows.
I wanted to make big moves
from the start and I did that.
I think the relationships
surprised me most about this game.
I thought I could come in here and
deceive people and vote them out
and I wouldn't feel bad about it.
But the truth is, you make
really close friendships here
and it really is difficult to
vote someone out of this game.
Oh, Wai!
I have wanted to play
this game for so long
and half a million dollars
is gonna change my life.
And just never, ever, ever giving
up, I think is the secret to winning.
I believe that the winner of Survivor
should be someone who possesses
physical, strategic and social game.
And, Hayley, you tick all the boxes.
Hayley, I think your game
was the most well rounded.
You've put a foot forward in everything.
You've worked best with so many people
that would still be on
your side at any moment.
You outwitted, outlasted and outplayed.
Well played.
I had to go with what I
think a true survivor is.
And to me, that was you, Hayley.
Not only am I so, so impressed
by your social, strategic
and physical game,
I'm amazed at how you owned
every single moment of that.
And I am so proud
to call you friend, ally
and hopefully Sole Survivor after this.